They’re dying to save the world.
The Suicide Squad is a action, comedy, adventure film directed by James Gunn.
Supervillains Harley Quinn, Bloodsport, Peacemaker and a collection of nutty cons at Belle Reve prison join the
super-secret, super-shady Task Force X as they are dropped off at the remote, enemy-infused island of Corto Maltese.
Harley Quinn, played by Margot Robbie.
Bloodsport, played by Idris Elba.
Peacemaker, played by John Cena.
Colonel Rick Flag, played by Joel Kinnaman.
King Shark (voice), played by Sylvester Stallone.
Amanda Waller, played by Viola Davis.
The Suicide Squad is a 2021 American superhero film
based on the DC Comics team Suicide Squad.
Written and directed by James Gunn, it is a standalone sequel to Suicide Squad
(2016) and the tenth film in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU).
The film stars an ensemble cast including Margot Robbie, Idris Elba, John Cena, Joel Kinnaman, David Dastmalchian, Daniela
Melchior, Michael Rooker, Jai Courtney, Peter Capaldi, Alice Braga, Pete Davidson, Sylvester Stallone, and Viola Davis.
In the film, several convicts join a task force known as the
"Suicide Squad" in exchange for lighter sentences.
They are sent to the South American island nation of Corto Maltese to destroy all traces of the giant
alien starfish Starro the Conqueror before it falls into the local government's control.
Warner Bros.
originally hired Gavin O'Connor to direct.
However, O'Connor left due to creative differences, and Gunn was hired to write and direct the film after
being temporarily fired by Disney and Marvel Studios as director of Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.
He drew inspiration from war films and John
Ostrander's 1980s Suicide Squad comics.
Filming took place from September 2019 to February 2020, primarily in
Atlanta, Georgia, as well as in Colón, Panama, and Porto, Portugal.
The film had the biggest sets ever built for a Warner Bros.
production.
The Suicide Squad premiered theatrically in the United Kingdom on July 30, 2021, and was released in the
United States on August 5, simultaneously in theaters and on the streaming service HBO Max.
Unlike its predecessor, the film received positive reviews from
critics and became the most-streamed DCEU film on HBO Max.
Nevertheless, the film fell short of projections, grossing $169
million against a $185 million production budget.
Its box office performance was attributed to factors such as the COVID-19 pandemic, the
film's availability on HBO Max, and its relationship to the first Suicide Squad.
It was followed by a spin-off television series, Peacemaker, in 2022,
and an animated series, Creature Commandos, in 2024.
A further television series, Waller, is in development.
The film explores themes of monster, secret mission,
superhero, anti hero, giant monster.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.